<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Thoughts while I learn stuff</title>
    <link>https://objectuser.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Thoughts while I learn stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 13:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://objectuser.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unbalanced Postgres Partitions</title>
      <link>https://objectuser.github.io/posts/2017-09-27-unbalanced-postgres-partitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 13:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://objectuser.github.io/posts/2017-09-27-unbalanced-postgres-partitions/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to partition a large table in Postgres. The table is approaching 500M rows. It had a sufficient number of rows that I was not able to create an index without running out of temporary storage on my cloud-hosted server.
Most of my reading on Postgres partitioning talked about partitioning by date. However, few of my queries are of the &amp;ldquo;recent rows&amp;rdquo; variety, so that didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like an optimal approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Rails Does the Wrong Thing</title>
      <link>https://objectuser.github.io/posts/2017-09-19-where-rails-does-the-wrong-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 10:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://objectuser.github.io/posts/2017-09-19-where-rails-does-the-wrong-thing/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of experience in Rails. I&amp;rsquo;ve used it over the last year, but most of my time during that period has been in Elixir.
Recently, due to how Postgres partial indexes work, I wanted to replace some parameter markers in my queries with manifest (i.e., hard coded) values. This was only for things like processing states and the like. I still wanted values like keys and dates to be parameterized for DB efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postgres Partial Indexes</title>
      <link>https://objectuser.github.io/posts/2017-09-17-postgres-partial-indexes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 09:48:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://objectuser.github.io/posts/2017-09-17-postgres-partial-indexes/</guid>
      <description>I have a large Postgres database that backs some data services used by a few other apps. This database is not large by Postgres standards, having about 600M rows.
I did some reading on Postgres indexes and decided that a series of partial indexes would likely provide the best performance for our variety of queries. However, I was confused that while my analysis revealed that the indexes I created would serve those queries well, Postgres never seemed to use them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>